Guide to the Harold Dwight Lasswell Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional material, 1952-1978; Accession 1988-M-049
  - General Files
    - Hermann, Charles F., 1975-1978 (Box 11, Folder 209)
    - Holmberg, Laura, 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 210)
    - Hopkins, Raymond F., 1972-1976 (Box 11, Folder 211)
    - Horowitz, Irving, 1976-1977 (Box 11, Folder 212-213)
    - Hutchins, Maude Phelps, 1973-1976 (Box 11, Folder 214)
    - Ic-Ins, 1970-1977, undated (Box 11, Folder 215)
    - Int, 1971-1977 (Box 11, Folder 216)
    - Io-Is, 1974-1976 (Box 11, Folder 217)
    - Iberall, Arthur S., 1975-1977 (Box 11, Folder 218)
    - Inaba, Morimitsu, 1975-1977, undated (Box 11, Folder 219)
    - Institute for World Order, Inc.
      See: box 102, folders 1242-1243
    - Institute of Social and Behavioral Pathology
      See: box 9, folders 168-169
    - Interacademy Bicentennial Committee, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 220)
    - International Conference on the Unity of Sciences, 1975 January-October (Box 11, Folder 221)
    - International Conference on the Unity of Sciences, 1975 November-1977, undated (Box 12, Folder 222-223)
    - International Peace Academy, 1976-1977, undated (Box 12, Folder 224)
    - International Society for Research on Aggression, 1973-1975 (Box 12, Folder 225)
    - International Studies Association, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 226)
    - Inter-University Seminar on Armed Forces and Society, 1975-1977 (Box 12, Folder 227)
    - Isard, Walter, 1969, 1973-1977, undated (Box 12, Folder 228-229)
    - J, 1968-1977 (Box 12, Folder 230)
    - Jaffey, Michael, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 231)
    - Janowitz, Morris, 1974-1977, undated (Box 12, Folder 232)
    - Jefferies, Jack P., 1971-1975, undated (Box 12, Folder 233)
    - Johns Hopkins University Press, 1977, undated (Box 12, Folder 234)
    - Jones, Dorothy B., 1973-1977, undated (Box 12, Folder 235)
    - Journal of Marketing Research, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 236)
    - Ka-Ke, 1973-1977 (Box 12, Folder 237)
    - Kh-Ko, 1970-1978 (Box 12, Folder 238)
    - Kr-Ky, 1973-1977 (Box 12, Folder 239)
    - Kaplan, Morton A., 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 240)
    - Kirkpatrick, Evron, 1974-1976 (Box 12, Folder 241)
    - Kirkpatrick, Jeane, 1973-1977 (Box 12, Folder 242)
    - Kochen, Manfred, 1973-1976 (Box 12, Folder 243)
    - Korff, Serge A., 1975-1977 (Box 12, Folder 244)
    - Kutner, Luis, 1970-1977, undated (Box 13, Folder 245-253)
    - La, 1970-1976, undated (Box 13, Folder 254)
    - Le, 1972-1977 (Box 13, Folder 255)
    - Li, 1971-1977 (Box 13, Folder 256)
    - Ll-Ly, 1968, 1971-1978 (Box 13, Folder 257)
    - Lamb, Robert B., 1973-1977, undated (Box 13, Folder 258-262)
    - Lamson, Robert W., 1974-1976 (Box 14, Folder 263)
    - Lander, Bernard
      See: box 22, folders 451-452
    - Leiserson, Avery, 1973-1976 (Box 14, Folder 264)
    - Lepawski, Albert, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 265)
    - Lerner, Daniel, 1972-1977, undated (Box 14, Folder 266-272)
    - Letiche, J. M., 1969, undated (Box 14, Folder 273)
    - Lewis, Paul M., 1975 (Box 14, Folder 274)
    - Lipson, Milton, 1974-1975, undated (Box 14, Folder 275)
    - Mac, 1973-1977 (Box 14, Folder 276)
    - Mad-Mar, 1969-1978 (Box 14, Folder 277)
    - Mas-Maz, 1973-1976 (Box 14, Folder 278)
    - Me, 1971-1976 (Box 14, Folder 279)
    - Mi, 1971-1976 (Box 14, Folder 280)
    - Mo-Mu, 1970-1977 (Box 14, Folder 281)
    - MIT Press, 1972-1977 (Box 14, Folder 282)
    - McCune, Sara Miller
    - MacDonald, Ronald St. John, 1973-1976 (Box 14, Folder 283)
    - McDougal, Myres S., 1973-1977 (Box 14, Folder 284-286)
    - McHale, John, 1970-1973 (Box 14, Folder 287-289)
    - McHale, John, 1974-1978, undated (Box 15, Folder 290-294)
    - McKenna, Jeremiah B., 1971-1977, undated (Box 15, Folder 295)
    - McKeown, Bruce, 1975-1976, undated (Box 15, Folder 296)
    - Marwick, Dwaine, 1974-1977, undated (Box 15, Folder 297-298)
    - Marwick, Elizabeth Wirth, 1971-1977 (Box 15, Folder 299-300)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1970-1976 (Box 15, Folder 301)
    - Mendolvitz, Saul, 1973-1977 (Box 15, Folder 302)
      See also: box 102, folders 1242-1243
    - Merritt, Richard L., 1975-1977 (Box 15, Folder 303)
    - Mershon Center
    - Milburn, Thomas W., 1972-1975 (Box 15, Folder 304)
    - Miller, Tom P., 1974-1977 (Box 15, Folder 305)
    - Modley, Rudolf, 1970, 1973-1976 (Box 15, Folder 306)
    - Montgomery, John D., 1972-1977, undated (Box 15, Folder 307-311)
    - Morehouse, Ward, 1975-1977, undated (Box 16, Folder 312)
    - Mudd, Emily H., 1969, 1973-1977, undated (Box 16, Folder 313)
    - Mudd, Stuart, 1969-1975, undated (Box 16, Folder 314)
    - Munro, Jim L., 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 315)
    - Muth, Rodney, 1974-1977 (Box 16, Folder 316)
    - Na, 1973-1977 (Box 16, Folder 317)
    - Ne-No, 1970-1977 (Box 16, Folder 318)
    - Nagai, Michio, 1973-1975, undated (Box 16, Folder 319)
    - Nagel, Stuart S., 1972-1977, undated (Box 16, Folder 320)
    - Nagi, Saad Z.
      See: box 17, folders 347-352
    - Namenwirth, Zvi J., 1969, 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 321)
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1973-1976 (Box 16, Folder 322-325)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1971-1977 (Box 16, Folder 326)
    - National Science Foundation, 1971, 1974, 1976-1977 (Box 16, Folder 327-329)
    - Nejelski, Leo, 1974-1976, undated (Box 16, Folder 330)
    - New York Academy of Sciences, 1970-1972 July (Box 16, Folder 331-335)
    - New York Academy of Sciences, 1972 September-1977, undated (Box 17, Folder 336-340)
    - New York State Legislative Institute, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 341)
    - Ng, Larry K. Y., 1968, 1972-1977 (Box 17, Folder 342-344)
    - Nolte, Richard, 1969-1971, 1975-1976 (Box 17, Folder 345)
    - O, 1971-1976 (Box 17, Folder 346)
    - Ohio State University Mershon Center, 1971-1977, undated (Box 17, Folder 347-352)
    - Olom, Louis T., 1973-1975 (Box 17, Folder 353)
    - Pa-Pe, 1971-1977 (Box 17, Folder 354)
    - Ph-Pl, 1970-1977 (Box 17, Folder 355)
    - Po-Pu, 1968, 1973-1977,undated (Box 17, Folder 356)
    - Padover, Saul K., 1973-1975 (Box 18, Folder 357)
    - Paige, Glenn D., 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 358)
    - Pelikan, Jaroslav, 1976-1977 (Box 18, Folder 359)
    - Penna, Frank J., 1972-1977, undated (Box 18, Folder 360-367)
    - Penniman, Howard, 1974, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 368)
    - Pepinsky, Harold B., 1973, 1975-1976, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 369)
    - Peyser, Minna Post, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 370)
    - Pierson, John H. G., 1976-1977 (Box 18, Folder 371)
    - Plenum Publishing Corporation, 1974-1976, undated (Box 18, Folder 372)
    - Policy Sciences Center, 1973-1976, undated (Box 18, Folder 373)
    - Pool, Ithiel De Sola, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 374)
    - Postman, Neil, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 375)
    - Pregel, Boris, 1968-1974 (Box 18, Folder 376-378)
    - Pregel, Boris, 1975-1976, undated (Box 18, Folder 379-380)
    - Princeton University Press, 1973-1975 (Box 18, Folder 381)
    - Pye, Lucian W., 1974-1976 (Box 18, Folder 382)
    - Quade, Edward S., 1971-1975 (Box 18, Folder 383)
    - Quirk, R. R., 1974 (Box 18, Folder 384)
    - Ra-Re, 1966, 1972-1975 (Box 18, Folder 385)
    - Ri, 1970-1977 (Box 18, Folder 386)
    - Ro, 1971-1976 (Box 19, Folder 387)
    - Ru, 1971-1977 (Box 19, Folder 388)
    - Rand Corporation, 1965, 1974-1976 (Box 19, Folder 389)
    - Rand Graduate Institute for Policy Sciences, 1972-1977 (Box 19, Folder 390-393)
    - Ranney, Austin J., 1974-1976 (Box 19, Folder 394)
    - Reisman, Michael W., 1973-1977 (Box 19, Folder 395)
    - Renshon, Stanley, 1973-1977, undated (Box 19, Folder 396)
    - Riverside Public Health Committee, 1973-1975, undated (Box 19, Folder 397)
    - Robins, Robert S., 1975 (Box 19, Folder 398)
    - Robinson, James A., 1959-1978 (Box 19, Folder 399-402)
    - Rogow, Arnold A., 1971-1977 (Box 19, Folder 403)
    - Ross, Douglas N., 1977 (Box 19, Folder 404)
    - Rosten, Leo, 1973-1977, undated (Box 19, Folder 405)
    - Rothman, Stanley, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 406)
    - Rothman, Stanley, 1975, undated (Box 20, Folder 407)
    - Rubenstein, Robert, 1973-1976, undated (Box 20, Folder 408)
    - Rubin, J. Seymour
    - Rubin, Louis J., 1974-1975 (Box 20, Folder 409)
    - Sa, 1969-1977 (Box 20, Folder 410)
    - Sc, 1969-1977 (Box 20, Folder 411)
    - Se-Sh, 1969-1977 (Box 20, Folder 412)
    - Si-Sl, 1970-1977 (Box 20, Folder 413)
    - Sm-So, 1969-1977, undated (Box 20, Folder 414)
    - Sp, 1973-1977 (Box 20, Folder 415)
    - St, 1970-1976 (Box 20, Folder 416)
    - Su-Sz, 1971-1977 (Box 20, Folder 417)
    - Sage Publications, Inc., 1972-1976 (Box 20, Folder 418)
    - Schacter, Oscar, 1973-1977 (Box 20, Folder 419)
    - Schuck, Victoria, 1974-1975 (Box 20, Folder 420)
    - Schuman, Frederick L., 1974-1978 (Box 20, Folder 421-423)
    - Shatan, Chaim F., 1961, 1969-1976 (Box 20, Folder 424-426)
    - Shatan, Chaim F.: files on the Ache Indians, undated (Box 21, Folder 427)
    - Shatan, Chaim F., undated (Box 21, Folder 428)
    - Shen, Benjamin S. P., 1974-1975 (Box 21, Folder 429)
    - Shubik, Martin, 1970-1977 (Box 21, Folder 430)
    - Siu, G. H., 1974-1975 (Box 21, Folder 431)
    - Smith, Bruce L., 1971-1978, undated (Box 21, Folder 432)
    - Snyder, Richard C.
    - Society Magazine
      See: box 22, folder 453
    - Solomon, Lewis D., 1975-1976, undated (Box 21, Folder 433)
    - Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, 1972-1976, undated (Box 21, Folder 434)
      See also: box 4, folder 75 See also: box 14, folders 266-272 See also: box 15, folders 307-311 See also: box 21, folder 443
    - Speier, Hans, 1973-1977, undated (Box 21, Folder 435-437)
    - Stern, H. Peter, 1973-1977 (Box 21, Folder 438)
    - Stewart, Milton David, 1974-1976, undated (Box 21, Folder 439)
    - Ta-Te, 1971-1977 (Box 21, Folder 440)
    - Th-To, 1973-1976 (Box 21, Folder 441)
    - Tr-Tz, 1970-1976 (Box 21, Folder 442)
    - Talbot, Phillips, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 443)
    - Tamayo y Salomoran, Rolando, 1973-1975 (Box 21, Folder 444)
    - Taylor, Harold, 1972-1973, undated (Box 21, Folder 445)
    - Temple University Press, 1974-1976 (Box 21, Folder 446)
    - Thompson, Whitney, 1973-1977 (Box 21, Folder 447-450)
    - Touro College, 1972-1975, undated (Box 22, Folder 451-452)
    - Transaction, Inc., 1976-1977, undated (Box 22, Folder 453)
    - Tyler, Ralph W., 1973-1974 (Box 22, Folder 454)
    - United Nations-United States, 1963-1964, 1972-1975 (Box 22, Folder 455)
    - Univ, 1970-1977 (Box 22, Folder 456)
    - U. S. Committee for the United Nations University, 1973-1974 (Box 22, Folder 457)
    - University of Chicago Press, 1973-1977 (Box 22, Folder 458)
    - V, 1972-1977, undated (Box 22, Folder 459)
    - Wa, 1971-1977 (Box 22, Folder 460)
    - We, 1974-1977 (Box 22, Folder 461)
    - Wh-Wi, 1972-1977 (Box 22, Folder 462)
    - Wo, 1971-1977 (Box 22, Folder 463)
    - Wr-Wy, 1973-1976 (Box 22, Folder 464)
    - Waller, Theodore, 1973-1977, undated (Box 22, Folder 465)
    - Warmbrunn, Joan S., 1972-1973, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 466)
    - Weisman, Milton C.
    - Wofford, Harris, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 467)
    - Wolf, Charles, Jr.
      See: box 19, folders 390-393
    - Wolfenstein, Victor, 1970-1973 (Box 22, Folder 468)
    - World Academy of Art and Science, 1963, 1968-1971 (Box 22, Folder 469-470)
      See also: box 48, folders 668-669 See also: box 14, folders 287-289 See also: box 16, folder 313 See also: box 16, folder 314 See also: box 18, folders 376-378 See also: box 22, folder 457
    - World Academy of Art and Science, 1972-1978, undated (Box 23, Folder 471-480)
    - World Academy of Art and Science: World University, 1969, 1972-1977 (Box 23, Folder 481-483)
    - World Federal Authority Committee, 1973-1975 (Box 23, Folder 484)
    - World Law Fund: World Order Models Project, 1968, 1970-1972 (Box 23, Folder 485-486)
    - World Man Fund
      See: box 17, folders 342-344
    - Wright, Harlan, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 487)
    - Y, 1966-1968, 1971-1975 (Box 24, Folder 488)
    - Young, Robert C., 1975-1976 (Box 24, Folder 489)
    - Yuhas, Alan, 1973-1977 (Box 24, Folder 490)
    - Z, 1973-1977 (Box 24, Folder 491)
    - Zawodny, J. K., 1977 (Box 24, Folder 492)
    - Zitta, Victor, 1968, 1974, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 493)
    - Unidentified, 1972-1976, undated (Box 24, Folder 494-495)
  - Topical Files
    - Africa (Box 24, Folder 496)
    - Apartment (Box 24, Folder 497)
    - Architecture (Box 24, Folder 498)
    - Charts, maps (Box 24, Folder 499)
    - Computer systems (Box 24, Folder 500)
    - Course material (Box 24, Folder 501)
    - Economics (Box 24, Folder 502)
    - Education (Box 24, Folder 503)
    - Elites (Box 24, Folder 504)
    - Environment, energy (Box 24, Folder 505)
    - Human dignity and global monitoring (Box 24, Folder 506)
    - India (Box 24, Folder 507)
    - Lists (Box 24, Folder 508)
    - Management (Box 25, Folder 509)
    - Netherlands (Box 25, Folder 510)
    - Psychology and politics (Box 25, Folder 511)
    - Sweden (Box 25, Folder 512)
    - Terrorism, aggression (Box 25, Folder 513)
    - United Nations University (Box 25, Folder 514)
  - Biographical Material and Personal Memorabilia
    Separated Materials
    The following audiocassettes were transferred to Historical Sound Recordings, Yale University Library: "A Political Scientist's View of the Future," Alternative Futures for Education and Learning: Symposium '73; William Benton Memorial Addresses (1973 Jun 11); and Franciscan Seminar. Researchers interested in these materials should contact Historical Sound Recordings (203 432-1795) to make an appointment.
    - Birthday memorabilia, 1976-1977 (Box 25, Folder 515)
    - Passports, 1970-1972 (Box 25, Folder 516)
    - Photographs, [1970s] (Box 25, Folder 517)
    - Pocket diaries, 1956-1959, 1961-1962, 1965-1966, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 519-520)
    - Pocket diaries, 1970-1973 (Box 26, Folder 521)
    - Pocket diaries, 1974-1976 (Box 26, Folder 522)
    - "The Social Process" produced by Encyclopaedia Britannica [commercially produced], Circa 1952-1953; 1 videotape (U-matic) (Box 27)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Yale Audiovisual was unable to play this tape on 1998 Apr 28.
      Conditions Governing Access
      Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
    - "The Social Process" produced by Encyclopaedia Britannica [commercially produced] Use copy, 1952; 1 (Box 27U)
    - Interview concerning the development of policy science, Circa 1970s; 2 (Box 28–29)
      - Duplicating master for boxes 28-29, 1 (Box 28D)
    - Interview concerning the development of policy science Use copy for boxes 28-29, 1 (Box 28U)
- Additional material, Accession 2010-M-039
  This addition is composed of correspondence, biographical material, personal memorabilia, and audio-visual materials received by W. Michael Reisman for the Lasswell Papers since 1991.
  Arrangement
  The material has been arranged in four sections and includes General Files, Writings, Biographical Material and Personal Memorabilia, and Speeches, Remarks, and Talks.
  - General files, 1949-1991
    - "American Political Science Association-Annual Convention-1974" [commercially-produced], 2 audiocassettes (Box 1–2)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica file: The Social Process, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Kutner, Luis, 1957-1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Matsuura, Yoshiharu, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Murchie, Guy, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Nagel, Stuart S., 1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Policy Sciences Center, 1969-1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Tomasic, Dinko, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - World Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Writings, 1947-1984, undated
    - General correspondence with various publishers, 1949-1977 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
    - An Analysis of H.G. Wells, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Communication and Propaganda in World History, Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Credit, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - The Elite Concept, 1947-1984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Formosa, China and the United Nations: Formosa in the World Community, Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - The Influence of Government, Undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - A Modern Paideia: Multivalued Analysis of the Socialization, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Opinion Systems in the Political Process, Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - The Philosophy of Liberation, Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - 'Political Man' or 'Decision Process', Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - The Political Realism of the World Habeas Corpus Proposal, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Political Science, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Political Science in the Atomic Age, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Projective Thinking, Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - The Significance for World Politcal Order of the Demand for Prompt, Impartial and Competent Hearing After Arrest, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - The Social Sciences in the Twentieth Century, Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - A Sophisticated View of Cycle Theory, Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - The Study of Personal Influence, Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Is Theory a Common Thread?, Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - The Value Institution Analysis of Mass Communication, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Value Synthesis: The Technique of Integrating Psychoanalysis awith Socioanalysis, Undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Biographical material and personal memorabilia, 1937-1999, undated
    - Biographical sketches, 1937-1999 (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
    - Biography by Miriam Ershkowitz, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Financial records, 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Harold D. Lasswell Estate, 1979-1993 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Biographical sketches of Linden Downey Lasswell and Anna Prather Lasswell, Undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - McDougal files concerning Lasswell's archive, 1949-1981 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - Miscellaneous notes, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Photographs of Lasswell, Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Bound volume of poetic writings by Lasswell, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Speeches, remarks, and talks, 1993, undated
    - "Alternative Futures for Education and Learning", Undated; 1 (Box 6)
    - "The Future of Government and Politics in the United States", Undated; 1 (Box 7)
    - "Lasswell Tape", Undated; 2 (Box 8–9)
    - "Pastoral Planning with Harold Lasswwell and Others", Undated; 1 (Box 10)
    - "Pastoral Planning with Harold Lasswell and Others", Undated; 1 (Box 11)
    - "Taking Education to the Skies...and Beyond", 1993; 1 (Box 12)